TEST CASE

CONTROLLER
JAVA

The Java Controller is a client (also referred as SUT, or System Under Test) which periodically connects to the server with an MySQL database, which determines which test to run in the SUT. 

The client is included in multiple SUTs and continuously executes the tests to test the SUT's major subsystems - such as memory, storage, CPU, netorking, and video capabilities. These tests are written in Python programming language, and each returns either SUCCESS or ERROR. If the latter, an error ocurring while testing the subsystem will also return the error description which the client will store in a local error log file.

Moreover, the client also sends back the test information to the server, in which the serves processes and stores the information in a database.

The client uses error handling to catch any exceptions while executing.

The only step is to run the client.