TEST CASE

PYTHON
CPU TEST

An example of a test to exercise CPU is a Python program that generates a random number from zero to one million, and iterates this process one million times. If time of execution meets time threshold, then the test is set as a SUCCESS. Use exception handling to determine if there is an error and print "ERROR:" with the error text. On success print "SUCCESS".

The program generates random number one million times to push CPU. The local Process Manager of the machine displays the amount of CPU utilizaion at the time of the testing. Here, the tester can visually analyze how CPU is impacted.

Moreover, the program checks for exception handling by throwing an error if there is a memory error in which the SUT ran out of memory (MemoryError) and is able to throw standard errors for error scenarios not previously, in order to avoid program to stop and not return any result to the controller.


=======================
Test Steps
=======================

1) SUCCESS scenario
Run the test configured to generate one million random numbers through a loop under an allowed time frame.
Expected result: Prints SUCCESS

2) Time exceeded scenario
This test makes sure the program handles the scenario where the Sis unable to fulfill the task within the allowed time. The error will be displayed and logged to a file in the SUT.
Expected result: Should print ERROR - The operation ran out of memory

3) CPU other exceptions scenario
This test ensures the program handles exceptions properly. Other error handlings "Excepts" are added to ensure defensive programming.
Expected result: Should print: ERROR - error message.
 
