TEST CASE

PYTHON
NETWORKING TEST

An example of a test to verify network connectivity is a Python program that opens a URL website, reads the contents and writes them unto a file in the local SUT. If the file is succesfully populated the URL contents, then network connectivity is a SUCCESS. Use exception handling to determine if there is an error and print "ERROR:" with the error text. On success print "SUCCESS".

The program saves the content unto a file and then checks the file size to ensure if it was populated with new data. The file is rewritten during each test to avoid the scenario in which the contents remain for a previous test. 

Moreover, the program checks for exception handling by throwing an error if there is no connection to the URL (URLError), if the server could not fulfill the request even though there is connectivity (HTTPError), if the file is not created (IOError), and is able to throw standard errors for error scenarios not previously, in order to avoid program to stop and not return any result to the controller.


=======================
Test Steps
=======================

1) SUCCESS scenario
Run the test configured to access a given URL, read the contents, write them unto a file, closes the file, then checks if the file contains a size bigger than 0.
Expected result: Prints SUCCESS

2) No network connection scenario
This test makes sure the program handles the scenario where the SUT cannot succesffully establish a network connection, which is marked as an ERROR test. Here, wifi on the SUT can be manually turned off to force the test error. Error will be logged to an error log file to verify the reason.
Expected result: Should print ERROR - There is no network connection

3) Network and other exceptions scenario
This test ensures the program handles exceptions properly. Other error handlings "Excepts" are added to ensure defensive programming.
Expected result: Should print: ERROR - error message.
 
