TEST CASE

PYTHON
STORAGE TEST

An example of a test to exercise storage is a Python program that creates and writes to a file 1000000 integers, closes the file, and repeats for a total of 20 times. Use exception handling to determine if there is an error and print "ERROR:" with the error text. On success print "SUCCESS".

The program creates the files within a loop. Storage is used as file is created, opened, written to, and closed. The time of execution (or list creation) in taken at the start and end of the process. The program defines a maximum processing time, in order to be considered a SUCCESS.

Moreover, the program checks for exception handling by throwing an error if the file attempting to be opened does not exist in the system, as well if the time of execution exceeds the maximum allowed time.


=======================
Test Steps
=======================

1) SUCCESS scenario
Run the test configured for 20 iterations of creating a one megabyte file to be written to
Expected result: Prints SUCCESS

2) Time exceeded scenario
This test makes sure the program handles the scenario where the runtime of the test exceeds a threshold, which is marked as an ERROR test. Here, time.sleep() function is implemented to add time to execution which will force an error. 
Expected result: Should print ERROR - Storage performance is poor

3) File does not exist scenario
Add a line to the code to force the program to force an exception on reading a file in "r" mode that does not exist. A line of code is used to delete the file used to test the error handling (os.remove), then the error exception of IOError is implemented.
Expected result: Should print ERROR - File not found
